CHRIS MCCARTHY

BALTIMORE, MD 21210 • CHRIS.S.MCCARTHY@GMAIL.COM • (610) 745-5866

OVERVIEW

A proven entrepreneur and project manager with extensive experience developing web and mobile applications, deploying cloud services and taking an idea to market. Developed and implemented award winning business plan. Redesigned systems and protocol for large NIH-funded brain imaging project; lead author for peer-reviewed publication. Recent Master's graduate of top ranked information management program.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, PHP, R, Python, Ruby on Rails, nodeJS, angularJS, Capistrano, Redis, ElasticSearch, D3, Phonegap/Cordova, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Visio, Adobe Illustrator, Strong written and verbal skills, Over 9 years of experience managing teams

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Information Management, Syracuse University Certificate of Advanced Studies, Data Science, Syracuse University Bachelor of Arts, Psychology, Syracuse University 2015 2015 2009

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chief Executive Officer/Founder Volu, Inc.

November 2014 – Present Syracuse, NY

- Created volunteer management software and received grant to incorporate company in January 2015
- Secured over \$50,000 through investments and competitions in the first year
- Grew user base to more than 40 organizations managing over 14,000 volunteers in 8 months following beta launch
- Selected as one of 6 businesses out of 70 applicants to participate in incubator providing funding and business development courses
- Embarked on cross country research and marketing trip meeting with close to 100 potential customers in 36 states while building base social media and blog following
- Implemented customer on-boarding and success strategy utilizing popular business communication tool Slack, resulting in a high conversion rate and most service requests being satisfied in less than 2 hours

Chief Technology Officer ChronicleMe, Inc.

August 2014 – March 2016 Syracuse, NY

- First hire for an early stage startup focusing on anonymous social networking
- Managed team of 4 developers and 1 designer
- Consolidated multiple existing Minimum Viable Products into single web and mobile application
- Migrated existing web server and database to cluster of cloud servers increasing scalability while reducing cost by over 60%
- Assisted Information Management Masters students in the creation of project plans to satisfy their course requirements and augmenting the company's capacity
- Presented technical progress and plan to potential investors and customers

Special Policy Analyst for the Chief Information Officer, Intern WYNIT, Inc.

March 2014 – August 2014 Syracuse, NY

- Direct report to Chief Information Officer cataloging and reviewing processes and policies
- Consolidated processes and policies from over 200 to less than 30 utilizing Janco Associates templates as a foundation
- Assisted project manager in managing timeline and risk for consolidating disparate management systems across company into single Enterprise Management System installation

Co-Chair, Civic Engagement Task Force, Board Member 40Below

April 2012 – March 2014 Syracuse, NY

■ Elected as co-chair of volunteering task force of Young Professional Organization and then to the board

- Organized and managed voter registration drive, job shadowing program and annual engagement event between local young professionals and college students
- Secured annual funding for task force and increased membership 400% during time as co-chair

Senior Research Support Specialist Upstate Medical University

May 2008 – March 2014 Syracuse, NY

- Worked for Principal Investigator on longitudinal study of 22q11.2 Syndrome, the second largest genetic predisposition to Schziophrenia
- Managed team of lab assistants in the measurement of brain structures on Magnetic Resonance Images
- Implemented automated measurement process using FreeSurfer software, ultimately increasing number of measurements able to be attained in a day from 16 to over 100
- Designed, executed and demonstrated the efficacy of fully automated brain segmentation methods over manual intervention leading to first authorship of a publication in a peer reviewed journal

CEO/Founder

May 2006 – May 2008 Swarthmore, PA

Fantasy Landscaping

- Grew from small operation to approximately 40 customers and an average of \$1000 in weekly profit
- Hired and managed crew of 3 to address growing demand

PUBLICATIONS

McCarthy, C. S., Ramprashad, A., Thompson, C., Botti, J. A., Coman, I. L., & Kates, W. R. (2015). A comparison of FreeSurfergenerated data with and without manual intervention. *Frontiers in neuroscience*, 9.

Radoeva, P. D., Coman, I. L., Antshel, K. M., Fremont, W., McCarthy, C. S., Kotkar, A., ... & Kates, W. R. (2012). Atlas-based white matter analysis in individuals with velo-cardio-facial syndrome (22q11. 2 deletion syndrome) and unaffected siblings. *Behavioral and Brain Functions*, 8(1), 1.

Hettema, J. M., Kettenmann, B., Ahluwalia, V., McCarthy, C., Kates, W. R., Schmitt, J. E., ... & Fatouros, P. (2012). Pilot multimodal twin imaging study of generalized anxiety disorder. *Depression and anxiety*, 29(3), 202-209.

Kates, W. R., Antshel, K. M., Faraone, S. V., Fremont, W. P., Higgins, A. M., Shprintzen, R. J., ... & McCarthy, C. (2011). Neuroanatomic predictors to prodromal psychosis in velocardiofacial syndrome (22q11. 2 deletion syndrome): a longitudinal study. *Biological psychiatry*, 69(10), 945-952.

PERSONAL AND ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- **Deadwood TV Show Analysis** Used Python, R and D3 to visualize the dialog of characters in a popular HBO TV show
- WhoIsIntoMe An web application developed in collaboration with Syracuse University professor Keisuke Inoue that performs a sentiment and activity analysis of a user's Facebook data to make a humorous prediction of who may be interested in them romantically
- Fitness App A web application, pre dating Apple Health, that kept track of important fitness metrics (i.e weight, sleep, etc.)
- **Risk App** A web application developed in Ruby on Rails and angularJS to calculate risk in a portfolio of projects, modeled after popular Risk Radar software
- Upstate Medical University Data Center Project Plan Lead a project team and worked with contact at Upstate Medical University in the creation of a waterfall style project plan for the implementation of a hypothetical data center

AWARDS

- First Place out of 1200 pitches, Social/Non-Profit category, 2016 New York Business Plan Competition
- 2014 40 Young Professionals Under 40 in Syracuse, NY Honoree

INTERESTS

■ 3-time Ironman Finisher